# João Pedro Ramos Cordeiro

# Software Developer

Location: Uberlândia, Minas Gerais, Brazil | Phone: +55 62 98280-7933 | Email: jpc5626@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/joaopedrorc

### **SUMMARY**

As a Software Developer with over 4 years of diverse experience, demonstrating a track record of top-quality code, adaptability with different teams and situations, attention to user experience, collaboration and problem-solving skills demonstrated across different successful projects. My expertise lies in JavaScript, Node.js, Typescript, and Golang. I excel in frameworks like React.js, Next.js, and Svelte.js, Express.js, along with Micro-Frontends. I have a passion for crafting clean and efficient code, implementing algorithms and data structures.

# **SKILLS**

**Proficient:** Javascript, Typescript, Next.js, React.js, CSS, HTML, Webpack, Vite, Babel, Jest, Cypress, React Testing Library, Storybook, Redux, Context Api, Server Side Rendering (SSR), API Rest, GraphQL, E2E testing, Unit testing, Performance testing, Git, DOM manipulation, PRPL pattern, DevTools.

Intermediate: Svelte.js, Angular.js, Micro-Frontends, Express.js, Postgres, MySQL, CI/CD, PWA.

Beginner: Golang, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, DevOps.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

BLU, Rio de Janeiro, BR – Remote

10/2021 to 11/2023

## **Core Responsibilities:**

- Member of the Frontend Engineering "B2B" and "Client Journey" teams responsible for the core products
  of Blu's business model. We're responsible for the "boleto" (bill) payments, Pagblu (BLU's main income
  source), Industry clients relationships and finance statistics.
- My contributions extended to delivering cutting-edge UI interfaces, notably leading the development of a
  groundbreaking product providing accurate credit information for industry clients to make informed
  decisions in selecting retailers.
- I orchestrated the organization of the Frontend Engineering team, efficiently distributing tasks, prioritizing assignments, and fostering a collaborative environment that ensured successful project deliveries. And I actively participated in the entire development lifecycle, conducting testing, code reviews, and engaging in team meetings to ensure the creation of high-quality, error-free products aligned with expectations and business goals.
- Member of Blu's open-source design system core Frontend Engineering, Ocean Ds. I was responsible for maintaining, upgrading, and creating new components, maintaining/refactoring existing components, code review, designing and implementing architectural decisions, managing team meetings, and much more.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** React.JS, Typescript, Valina Javascript, HTML 5, CSS 3, Rails ERB template, Webpack, Module Federation, Micro Frontends, Styled Components, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Storybook, Formik, Axios, Yup Forms, Webpack, Babel, GraphQL, Rest, Redux, Context API, Git, Github, Agile Methodology (Scrum), Jira, Open source maintainer, Open source projects, Sass CSS, Chromatic, Commitlint, Github Projects.

#### PLENO FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Everis an NTT DATA Company, São Paulo, BR - Remote

05/2021 to 10/2021

# **Core Responsibilities:**

- Member of the Frontend Engineering team responsible for developing the Rede D'or HR-Digital
  Application, a PWA (Progressive Web App built with React.js, Typescript and Redux), responsible for
  providing mobility and simplicity for Rede D'or employees. I was responsible for bringing the App's design
  and functionality to life, following the best programming and software design practices.
- Member of the Frontend Engineering team responsible for the Frontend migration of the Santander IBPJ (Corporate Internet Banking), written in ASP (Active Server Pages), application responsible for the centralization and management of users, profiles, passwords, registration data and tokens of clients from Santander. I was responsible for migrating, developing and testing various sections/menus of the system.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** React.js, Styled Components, Base Web, GIT, Github, Azure DevOps (Team Foundation Service - TFS), Agile Methodology (Scrum, Kanban), Development of a PWA, Typescript, CMS - WordPress, HTML 5, CSS 3, BItbucket, Atlassian (Jira Work Management), Angular JS, Bootstrap, Testing (Karma and Jasmine test framework), Jenkins Pipeline com Sonarqube, Gitlab.

#### JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Everis an NTT DATA Company, São Paulo, BR - Remote

08/2020 to 05/2021

# **Core Responsibilities:**

- Member of the Frontend Engineering team member responsible for Sismed UHG Brazil (Unitedhealth Group Brazil) portal migration written in Adobe Flex. The application is responsible for managing the reception area in hospitals and medical clinics throughout Brazil.
- Tasked with transforming legacy Adobe Flex codebase into modern, responsive React components, ensuring enhanced performance and usability for users accessing vital healthcare services across Brazil.
- I gained insights into system architecture by navigating the complexities of transitioning the legacy Adobe
  Flex codebase to modern React.js components. I explored various code patterns and best practices while
  optimizing performance and usability for healthcare professionals and patients.
- Additionally, I developed project management skills by watching and participating in cross-functional teams, ensuring seamless migration and implementation of critical software solutions within tight deadlines and regulatory standards.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** React.js, HTML 5, CSS 3, Styled Components, Base Web Component Library, GIT, Github, Azure DevOps (Team Foundation Service - TFS), Agile Methodology (Scrum, Kanban).

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Mechanical Engineer**

Universidade Federal de Uberlândia, Minas Gerais, Brazil 08/2019 to 08/2024

### **CERTIFICATION/COURSES**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (Az-900), Microsoft 09/2020

Goiás Without Borders Exchange Program, New Jersey City University, US 11/2017

Cross Community Engagement Peace Ambassador Workshop, New Jersey City University, US 12/2017

#### LANGUAGES

**Portuguese:** Native **English:** Fluent - C1